The Messenger: The Story of Joan of Arc is a adventure,
drama, action film directed by Luc Besson.
In 1429, a French teenager stood before her King with a message she claimed came from God; that she would
defeat the world's greatest army and liberate her country from its political and religious turmoil.
As she reclaims God's diminished kingdom, this courageous young woman has
various amazing victories until her violent and untimely death.
Joan of Arc, played by Milla Jovovich.
Charles VII, played by John Malkovich.
Yolande of Aragon, played by Faye Dunaway.
Joan's conscience, played by Dustin Hoffman.
The Duke of Alençon, played by Pascal Greggory.
Gilles de Rais, played by Vincent Cassel.
The Messenger: The Story of Joan of Arc (French: Jeanne d'Arc) is a 1999 English-language French epic historical drama
film directed by Luc Besson and starring Milla Jovovich, John Malkovich, Faye Dunaway and Dustin Hoffman.
The screenplay was written by Besson and Andrew Birkin, and
the original score was composed by Éric Serra.
The Messenger portrays the story of Joan of Arc, the French war
heroine and religious martyr of the Hundred Years' War.
It begins with young Joan as she witnesses the atrocities of the English against her family, and she
has visions that inspire her to lead the French in battle against the occupying English.
Her success in routing the English allows Charles VII to take the throne.
Eventually, Joan is captured by the English, tried and executed for heresy.
Besson's previous film, The Fifth Element (1997), which also stars Jovovich, was a critical
and financial success, and had a positive influence on both of their careers.
The Messenger was intended to follow that success and
cement Besson's and Jovovich's status in film.
However, it received mixed-to-negative reviews and underperformed at the box
office, earning just $67 million on a $60 million budget.
The film explores themes of rape, france, politics, necrophilia, siege.
The tone is dark and emotional.